Guide to the University of Hartford and Hillyer College public relations scrapbooks ARCH145
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
University of Hartford and Hillyer College public relations scrapbooks
1953-1985
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH145
9.25 Linear Feet (37 containers)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Historical Note
The early history of the University was faithfully documented by staff members who regularly clipped newspaper articles and pasted them into scrapbooks year by year. This practice was apparently discontinued sometime in the mid-1980s.
Some scrapbooks were marked as from the University's Department of Public Information and others from the News Bureau. The scrapbooks most likely originated from staff from Hillyer College and the University offices responsible for public relations, marketing, and communication.
Scope and Contents
These folio size scrapbooks contain an extensive collection of newspaper clippings documenting how the university was treated by the press for three decades as well as advertising campaigns in newspapers and publications created by the University. Finally, the collection also contains University publications such as leaflets, pamphlets, brochures, and booklets.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: I. Newspaper Clippings; II. Advertising Campaigns; III. Publications
University of Hartford; Hillyer College
- Clippings, 1953-1985; I
  - 1953 Sep - 1956 Jun (Box 1)
  - 1956 Jul 5 - 1957 Jul 23 (Box 1)
  - 1957 Jul 7 - 1958 Apr 10 (Box 2)
  - 1958 Apr 10 - Dec 31 (Box 2)
  - 1959 Jan 1 - Nov 30 (Box 2)
  - 1958 May - 1959 Apr (Box 3)
  - 1959 Feb 27 - 1960 May (Box 4)
  - 1959 Aug - 1960 May (Box 4)
  - 1960 May 28 - 1962 Apr 16 (Box 4)
  - 1960 Jun 1 - 1961 Mar 11 (Box 5)
  - 1961 Jan 26 - 1962 Feb 12 (Box 5)
  - 1961 Sep 9 - 1962 Aug 30 (Box 5)
  - 1962 Feb 13 - 1963 May 26 (Box 5)
  - 1963 May 22 - 1964 Jul 8 (Box 6)
  - 1964 Jun 12 - 1965 Sep 22 (Box 6)
  - 1965 Sep 2 - 1966 May 14 (Box 6)
  - 1966 May 26 - Nov 18 (Box 7)
  - 1966 Nov 17 - 1967 May 9 (Box 7)
  - 1967 May 7 - Oct 5 (Box 7)
  - 1967 Oct 5 - 1968 Jan 31 (Box 8)
  - 1968 Feb 1 - May 23 (Box 8)
  - 1968 May 23 - Sep 5 (Box 8)
  - 1968 Sep 5 - Nov 30 (Box 8)
  - 1968 Dec 1 - 1969 Mar 16 (Box 9)
  - 1969 Mar 16 - Oct 31 (Box 9)
  - 1969 Nov 1 - 1970 Mar 31 (Box 10)
  - 1970 Apr 1 - 1971 Feb 28 (Box 11)
  - 1971 Mar 1 - May 5 (Box 10)
  - 1971 May 06 - Jun 30 (Box 10)
  - 1971 Jul 1 - Sep 31 (Box 12)
  - 1971 Oct 1 - Dec 17 (Box 12)
  - 1972 Mar 1 - Apr 9 (Box 12)
  - 1972 May 1 - Aug 31 (Box 13)
  - 1972 Sep 1 - Nov 30 (Box 13)
  - 1972 Nov 30 - 1973 Feb 21 (Box 13)
  - 1973 Feb 22 - Aug 31 (Box 14)
  - 1973 Sep 1 - 1974 Feb 28 (Box 14)
  - 1974 Mar 1 - Apr 30 (Box 14)
  - 1974 May 1 - Dec 13 (Box 15)
  - 1974 Dec 14 - 1975 Mar 13 (Box 15)
  - 1975 (Box 15)
  - 1975 Mar 13 - Jun 30 (Box 16)
  - 1975 Nov 1 - 1976 Jan 29 (Box 16)
  - 1976 Apr 1 - Jul 14 (Box 16)
  - 1976 Jun 30 - 1977 May 8 (Box 17)
  - 1976 Jul 15 - Oct 28 (Box 17)
  - 1976 Oct 29 - 1977 Jan 2 (Box 17)
  - 1977 Jan 3 - Jun 23 (Box 18)
  - 1977 Jun 24 - Aug 3 (Box 19)
  - 1977 Aug 3 - Sep 28 (Box 19)
  - 1977 Sep 26 - Nov 4 (Box 19)
  - 1977 Dec 2 - 1978 Jan 31 (Box 20)
  - 1978 Feb 1 - Mar 9 (Box 20)
  - 1978 Mar 9 - Dec 18 (Box 20)
  - 1978 Feb 27 - Dec 11 (Box 21)
  - 1978 Jun - Sep (Box 21)
  - 1978 Oct - Dec (Box 21)
  - 1979 Book One, 1979 Jan 1 - Mar 9 (Box 22)
  - 1979 Book Two, 1979 Mar 9 - Apr 30 (Box 22)
  - 1979 Book Three, 1979 May 1 - Jul 31 (Box 22)
  - 1979 Book Four, 1979 Aug 1 - Oct 31 (Box 23)
  - 1979 Book Five, 1979 Nov 1 - Dec 27 (Box 23)
  - 1979 Apr - May (Box 23)
  - 1980 Book One, 1980 Jan 1 - Mar 31 (Box 23)
  - 1980 Book Two, 1980 Apr 1 - Jun 15 (Box 24)
  - 1980 Book Three, 1980 Jun 15 - Sep 30 (Box 24)
  - 1980 Book Four, 1980 Oct 1 - Nov 15 (Box 24)
  - 1980 Jan 31 - Dec 26 (Box 25)
  - 1981 Jan - May (Box 25, Box 26)
  - 1981 Jun 2 - Dec 27 (Box 26)
  - 1982 Jan - Jun (Box 27)
  - 1982 Jan 4 - Jun 11 (Box 27)
  - 1982 Jul - Dec (Box 28)
  - 1983 Jan - Jun (Box 28, Box 29)
  - 1983 Jul - Dec (Box 29)
  - 1985 Aug - Sep (Box 30)
- Advertising Campaigns, 1953 Feb - 1986 Sep; II
  - 1953 Feb - 1958 Sep (Box 30)
  - 1964 Mar - 1966 Jun (Box 30)
  - 1966 Fall - 1968 Fall (Box 30)
  - 1968 Nov - 1970 Sep (Box 30)
  - 1970 Nov - 1973 Jun (Box 31)
  - 1973 Jul - 1986 Sep (Box 31)
- Publications, 1968-1985; III
  - 1968-1969 (Box 32)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 32)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 32)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 33)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 33)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 33)
  - 1975-1977 (Box 34)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 34)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 35)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 35)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 36)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 36)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 37)